2021 B-DATE
Annual O
Report O
Royal B-ORG
FrieslandCampina I-ORG
N.V. I-ORG
| O
43 O
Partnerships O
with O
customers O
Cooperating O
to O
create O
a O
positive O
impact O
forms O
part O
of O
our O
culture O
. O
We O
refer O
to O
this O
as O
cooperative O
sustainability O
. O
For O
us O
, O
this O
means O
close O
cooperation O
with O
stakeholders O
, O
including O
customers O
, O
to O
achieve O
sustainable O
developments O
at O
farms O
and O
make O
products O
sustainable O
. O
In B-DATE
2021 I-DATE
, O
we O
invested O
with O
customers O
in O
accelerating O
the O
reduction O
of O
greenhouse O
gases O
and O
promoting O
sustainable O
developments O
at O
the O
farms O
of O
our O
member O
dairy O
farmers O
. O
Supplying O
ingredients O
and O
products O
with O
a O
lower O
carbon O
footprint O
to O
our O
customers O
is O
an O
example O
of O
this O
. O
With O
these O
partnerships O
, O
we O
not O
only O
contribute O
to O
lowering O
own O
carbon O
footprint O
, O
but O
we O
also O
support O
our O
customers O
by O
enabling O
them O
to O
offer O
products O
with O
a O
lower O
footprint O
under O
their O
brands O
. O
In O
addition O
, O
we O
also O
carried O
out O
pilot O
projects O
for O
feed O
additives O
to O
reduce O
the O
emission O
of O
greenhouse O
gases O
, O
including O
the O
partnership O
with O
Barry B-ORG
Callebaut I-ORG
, O
Agolin B-ORG
and O
Agrifirm B-ORG
. O
‘ O
On B-nutritionalLabel
the I-nutritionalLabel
way I-nutritionalLabel
to I-nutritionalLabel
PlanetProof I-nutritionalLabel
’ I-nutritionalLabel
The O
independent O
‘ O
On B-nutritionalLabel
the I-nutritionalLabel
way I-nutritionalLabel
to I-nutritionalLabel
PlanetProof I-nutritionalLabel
’ I-nutritionalLabel
sustainability O
quality O
label O
for O
dairy O
products O
of O
the O
Stichting B-ORG
Milieukeur I-ORG
[ O
Environmental B-ORG
Quality I-ORG
Mark I-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
] O
became O
one O
of O
the O
fastest-growing O
sustainability O
quality O
labels O
in O
the O
Netherlands B-LOC
in O
2021 B-DATE
. O
267 B-PERCENTAGE
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
fresh O
dairy O
and O
cheese O
products O
with O
the O
‘ O
On B-nutritionalLabel
the I-nutritionalLabel
way I-nutritionalLabel
to I-nutritionalLabel
PlanetProof I-nutritionalLabel
' I-nutritionalLabel
quality O
label O
were O
available O
in O
2021 B-DATE
. O
This O
represents O
a O
growth O
of O
9 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
in O
comparison O
to O
2020 B-DATE
and O
more O
than O
25.6 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
in O
comparison O
to O
2019 B-DATE
. O
In O
2021 B-DATE
, O
Campina B-ORG
Quark I-ORG
also O
became O
available O
under O
this O
quality O
label O
. O
The O
milk O
comes O
from O
member O
dairy O
farmers O
who O
perform O
well O
on O
multiple O
themes O
simultaneously O
: O
animal O
welfare O
, O
biodiversity O
and O
climate O
. O
Six B-NUM
sustainable O
priorities O
The O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
sustainability O
programme O
presented O
at O
the O
end O
of O
2020 B-DATE
, O
Nourishing B-ORG
a I-ORG
better I-ORG
planet I-ORG
, O
includes O
six B-NUM
priorities O
. O
This O
provides O
a O
greater O
focus O
to O
our O
efforts O
of O
accelerating O
global O
sustainability O
themes O
. O
We O
will O
also O
continue O
to O
devote O
full O
attention O
to O
themes O
such O
as O
human O
rights O
and O
animal O
welfare O
. O
In O
2021 B-DATE
, O
we O
saw O
that O
this O
refined O
focus O
was O
bearing O
fruit O
in O
terms O
of O
the O
business O
group O
and O
brand-related O
developments O
. O
Better O
nutrition O
, O
affordable O
for O
everyone O
Our O
aim O
is O
to O
comply O
with O
the O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
Global B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
Next I-nutritionalLabel
Level I-nutritionalLabel
and O
to O
expand O
access O
to O
nutrition O
for O
lower O
income O
groups O
throughout O
the O
world O
. O
Milk B-NUTRIENT
naturally O
contains O
valuable O
nutrients O
, O
such O
as O
high-quality O
proteins B-NUTRIENT
, O
vitamins B-NUTRIENT
B2 I-NUTRIENT
and O
B12 I-NUTRIENT
, O
calcium B-NUTRIENT
, O
potassium B-NUTRIENT
, O
phosphorous B-NUTRIENT
and O
magnesium B-NUTRIENT
. O
That O
makes O
milk O
products O
unique O
foods O
that O
are O
recommended O
in O
nutritional O
guidelines O
throughout O
the O
world O
. O
Balance O
and O
composition O
of O
the O
product O
range O
In O
2021 B-DATE
, O
71 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
of O
FrieslandCampina's B-ORG
products O
, O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
sales O
volume O
, O
complied O
with O
the O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
Global B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
Next I-nutritionalLabel
Level I-nutritionalLabel
( O
2025 B-DATE
target O
: O
minimum O
74 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
) O
. O
The O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
Global B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
are O
scientific O
nutritional O
criteria O
that O
our O
own O
consumer O
products O
are O
expected O
to O
comply O
with O
. O
The O
criteria O
for O
trans-fat B-NUTRIENT
, O
saturated-fat B-NUTRIENT
, O
added O
sugar B-NUTRIENT
and O
salt B-NUTRIENT
are O
derived O
from O
Choices B-ORG
International I-ORG
Report O
by O
the O
Executive O
Board O
_ O
Nourishing B-nutritionalLabel
a I-nutritionalLabel
better I-nutritionalLabel
planet I-nutritionalLabel
Choices B-ORG
International I-ORG
2019 B-DATE
to O
create O
the O
new O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
Global B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
Next I-nutritionalLabel
Level I-nutritionalLabel
. O
73 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
of O
the O
product O
supply O
consists O
of O
'basic B-nutritionalLabel
nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
products I-nutritionalLabel
for I-nutritionalLabel
daily I-nutritionalLabel
consumption I-nutritionalLabel
' O
and O
27 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
consists O
of O
'self-indulgent B-nutritionalLabel
products I-nutritionalLabel
for I-nutritionalLabel
occasional I-nutritionalLabel
consumption I-nutritionalLabel
’ O
( O
on O
the O
basis O
of O
sales O
volume O
) O
. O
The O
objective O
is O
a O
proportion O
of O
at O
least O
70 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
basic B-nutritionalLabel
nutrition I-nutritionalLabel
and O
a O
maximum O
of O
30 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
self-indulgent B-nutritionalLabel
products I-nutritionalLabel
. O
Access O
to O
nutrition O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
aims O
to O
increase O
access O
to O
healthy O
food O
, O
in O
particular O
dairy B-nutritionalLabel
products I-nutritionalLabel
, O
specifically O
for O
less O
privileged O
consumers O
for O
whom O
this O
is O
not O
self-evident O
, O
for O
example O
due O
to O
lower O
income O
. O
Shortages O
of O
nutrients O
, O
such O
as O
iodine B-NUTRIENT
, O
vitamin B-NUTRIENT
A I-NUTRIENT
and O
iron B-NUTRIENT
, O
are O
a O
threat O
to O
the O
health O
of O
individuals O
, O
especially O
in O
these O
groups O
. O
We O
do O
this O
by O
offering O
products O
in O
our O
lower O
disposable O
income O
markets O
( O
such O
as O
Indonesia B-LOC
, O
Vietnam B-LOC
, O
the O
Philippines B-LOC
, O
Pakistan B-LOC
, O
Nigeria B-LOC
and O
the O
Ivory B-LOC
Coast I-LOC
) O
with O
a O
tailored O
price O
and O
packaging O
proposition O
through O
channels O
that O
are O
specific O
to O
reaching O
these O
target O
groups O
. O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
has O
evaluated O
the O
‘Affordable B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
’ I-nutritionalLabel
and O
has O
incorporated O
them O
into O
the O
Global B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
Next I-nutritionalLabel
Level I-nutritionalLabel
. O
These O
are O
scientific O
nutritional O
criteria O
that O
ensure O
such O
products O
contain O
the O
right O
nutrients O
needed O
to O
counter O
malnutrition O
. O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
aims O
to O
increase O
the O
share O
of O
these O
affordable O
nutritional B-nutritionalLabel
products I-nutritionalLabel
to O
at O
least O
15 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
in O
our O
low O
income O
markets O
. O
In B-DATE
2021 I-DATE
this O
was O
12 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
. O
In O
these O
countries O
approximately O
30 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
of O
the O
population O
has O
a O
low O
income O
. O
To O
counter O
malnutrition O
, O
we O
optimise O
protein B-NUTRIENT
quality O
and O
quantity O
, O
in O
addition O
to O
adding O
the O
right O
mix O
of O
vitamins B-NUTRIENT
and O
minerals B-NUTRIENT
, O
of O
all O
affordable O
nutrition O
products O
. O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
aims O
to O
have O
50 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
of O
the O
volume O
of O
affordable O
nutrition O
products O
sold O
in O
low O
income O
countries O
comply O
with O
the O
Affordable B-nutritionalLabel
Nutritional I-nutritionalLabel
Standards I-nutritionalLabel
by O
2025 B-DATE
. O
In B-DATE
2021 I-DATE
this O
was O
5 B-PERCENTAGE
percent I-PERCENTAGE
. O
For O
more O
information O
about O
this O
programme O
visit O
our O
website O
. O
In O
addition O
to O
making O
nutrition O
and O
milk B-NUTRIENT
accessible O
and O
affordable O
, O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
in O
2021 B-DATE
provided O
food O
aid O
by O
supplying O
products O
to O
food O
banks O
in O
the O
Netherlands B-LOC
and O
through O
school O
milk B-NUTRIENT
programmes O
in O
countries O
in O
Europe B-LOC
, O
Asia B-LOC
and O
Africa B-LOC
. O
2021 B-DATE
Annual O
Report O
Royal B-ORG
FrieslandCampina I-ORG
N.V. I-ORG
| O
44 O
Largescale O
nutrition O
and O
health O
survey O
in O
Southeast B-LOC
Asia I-LOC
In B-DATE
2021 I-DATE
, O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
finished O
collecting O
data O
for O
the O
South B-ORG
East I-ORG
Asian I-ORG
Nutrition I-ORG
Survey I-ORG
II I-ORG
(SEANUTS B-ORG
II I-ORG
) O
; O
one O
of O
the O
largest O
nutrition O
research O
projects O
in O
Southeast B-LOC
Asia I-LOC
. O
Data O
was O
collected O
about O
nutrition O
, O
health O
and O
lifestyle O
for O
more O
than O
13,000 O
children O
in O
Thailand B-LOC
, O
Malaysia B-LOC
, O
Indonesia B-LOC
and O
Vietnam B-LOC
, O
ranging O
in O
age O
from O
six O
months O
up O
to O
and O
including O
twelve O
years O
. O
FrieslandCampina B-ORG
works O
together O
with O
leading O
universities O
and O
knowledge O
institutes O
in O
the O
region O
for O
this O
purpose O
. O
On O
the O
basis O
of O
new O
scientific O
insights O
we O
will O
develop O
education O
and O
better O
nutritional O
products O
that O
meet O
local O
needs O
. O
This O
is O
consistent O
with O
FrieslandCampina’s B-ORG
goal O
of O
providing O
nutrition O
to O
the O
world O
population O
. O
The O
results O
will O
be O
announced O
in O
June B-DATE
2022 I-DATE
. O
